* The open road *
* is on my back today *
♬ AM / FM Sound ♬
Matt and Kim
* hold me up *
* I'm sure not to drag away *
* all these twists and turns *
* piles of dreams and dimes *
비아워비에자 삼림지대
= 폴란드 =
* I'll take what's in front *
* and leave this mess behind *
Come on up here. We're almost there.
얼른 와
거의 다 왔어
거의 다 온 게
10킬로미터나 남았지
Come on, Reva, hasn't a week of hiking
그만해, 리바
일주일 동안의 등산이
전혀 즐겁지 않았어?
been at all fun for you? I am in tech ops.
난 기술 요원이야
I enjoy HDTV cameras the size of dimes
내가 즐기는 건
동전 크기의
고화질 카메라나
and playing with lasers.
레이저 가지고
노는 거야
See, this is the greatest part about our job.
이게 우리 직업의
가장 좋은 점이야
We fly halfway around the world and spend a week in an amazing place.
지구 절반을
날아와서
이렇게 멋진 장소에서
일주일이나 보내잖아
Seeing things like this. It's very pretty.
이런 경치도 보고
정말 예쁘네
I'm sure it's also pretty when you look at it on Google Earth.
구글 어스로 봐도
분명히 예쁠 거야
From...Yeah.
- 이 위치로
- 그래
If you don't like being in the field, why'd you take this assignment?
현장에 나오기
싫으면서
이번 임무는
왜 하겠다고 했어?
Because it's a great opportunity to shepherd a new piece of technology.
왜냐하면
신기술을 시연할
둘도 없는 기회니까
I mean, you know what it means to build your bones at the agency.
기관에서 치고 올라간다는 게
무슨 뜻인지 알잖아
You press for key missions, succeed,
중요한 임무를 부여받아
성공시키고
and then ride that success all the way to your own department
그 성공을 발판으로
자기만의 부서를 갖는 거야
where you no longer have to go into the field.
그럼 다시는 현장에
나갈 필요가 없지
I think this is as close as we can get
여기가 벨로루시
국경을 넘지 않고
to the Belarusian border without crossing it.
Excellent.
가장 가까이 접근할 수
있는 지점 같아
좋았어
You know how many nights I spent
얼마나 많은 밤을
실험실에서 지새며
at the lab triple-checking every circuit
모든 회로를 수도 없이
확인했는지 알아?
and trying to impress my supervisors by refining the filters?
필터 성능을
개선시켜서
내 상관들에게
잘 보이려 애쓰면서?
And now, I don't know,
it's just really, really cool
이젠...
글쎄
마침내 이걸 작동시킨다는 게
정말이지 멋진 일 같아
to finally see these things in action.
Okay.
됐어
Great, everything looks good on my end.
All right, I'll call it in.
좋아, 이쪽은
문제 없어 보여
알았어
내가 연락할게
Border photography and logistics.
This is your Captain speaking.
국경 사진 및
물류 지원팀입니다
여긴 여러분의
캡틴입니다
Hey, Aug. Last one fired and ready to go.
반가워요, 오기
마지막 기계 설치하고
갈 준비 됐어요
All right, hold on.
알았어요
잠깐만요
You have it?
나와요?
Annie, the signal's bouncing off of four different satellites.
애니, 신호가 4개의
위성을 지나야 해요
You're gonna have to give it a minute.
잠시 시간을
주셔야겠습니다
Sorry. I'm a little excited to get going.
미안해요
돌아간다는 사실에
약간 들떠서요
Finally get a chance to hike the Orla Perc Trail
on your way home, huh, Walker?
마침내 돌아오는 길에
올라 퍼크 산길에
가볼 기회가 생겨서요?
워커 요원?
How did you know I was gonna do that?
그럴 생각인지
어떻게 알았어요?
When are you gonna realize I know everything?
난 모든 걸 안다는 사실을
언제쯤 깨달을래요?
I don't know whether to be scared or oddly comforted by that.
그래서
무서운 건지
묘하게 편한 건지
잘 모르겠네요
Oh, comforted for sure,
물론 편한 쪽이겠죠
especially because I reworked your travel back to Warsaw.
더구나 바르샤바로
돌아가는 길을
내가 다시
손써뒀으니까요
The Polish government is so grateful that we're sharing these photos with them
폴란드 정부에서 우리가
사진을 공유해주는 것에 대한
that they've offered you a ride to the airport.
감사의 표시로
공항까지 태워주겠대요
Ah...Reva will love you forever.
리바가 당신을
영원토록 사랑하겠네요
Why is that?
왜?
- Taxi to the airport. - Hmm, I don't love Auggie,
공항까지 택시 탄대
오기를 사랑하진 않지만
그건 고맙네
but I'm appreciative of the ride. She's thinking about it.
생각 중이에요
She's obsessed with me. All right, we've got a feed.
리바는 나한테
푹 빠졌죠
좋아요
자료가 들어왔어요
- Okay, are we good to go? - Indeed.
- 이제 가도 돼요?
- 맞아요
Enjoy the ride. Get home safe.
교통편 잘 이용하고
- 조심해서 돌아와요
- 그럴게요
Will do.
All right, let's get outta here. Hot shower, here I come.
좋아
이제 돌아가자
온수 샤워여
기다려라
Wait, there's something on the Belarusian side
that's not on the map.
잠깐
지도에 없는 뭔가가
벨로루시 쪽에 있어
Looks like a town, but there aren't any people in it.
마을 같은데
사람이 아무도 없어
That's weird.
이상한걸
Reva.
리바?
리바
-==팎읔襟있蹈==- 굶俚캥쏭묩欺構슥직, 拮쐐痰黨庚둡촐
영자막 elderman
www.addic7ed.com
-==http://www.ragbear.com==- 줅소큽景묏 뒤랗센뒤6섞
Season 2 Episode 6
The Outsiders
-=팎읔襟俚캥莉=- 럇陋： 叫뚤： 珂쇌菉:kami
한글번역 에렝아이
디시인사이드 기미갤
Annie, what's happening? What did he say?
애니, 어떻게 된 거야?
뭐라고 하는데?
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND.
이해를 못 하시는군요
WE'ARE JUST TOURIST.
우린 그냥 여행객이에요
WE'VE DONE NOTHING WRONG.
잘못한 거 없어요
Damn it, there's no internal latch.
젠장! 안쪽엔
손잡이가 없어
The best time for escape is en route. I know.
탈출에 최적의 시기는
이동 중일 때야 / 알아
그러지 못하면 생존 확률이
급격히 낮아질 거야
Otherwise our chances of survival diminish greatly.
I mean, statistically speaking.
그러니까...
통계적으로 말이야
Let's think. The rock camera was on.
생각을 해보자
암석 카메라가
작동 중이야
It would have caught the license plate of the truck.
이 트럭의 번호판이
찍혔을지도 몰라
Langley will see that and contact the Polish embassy right away.
랭리에서 보고
폴란드 대사관에
연락할 수도 있어
Yes, except this truck didn't have a license plate.
맞아, 하지만 이 트럭엔
번호판이 없어
뭐?
- Are you sure? - Yeah.
- 정말이야?
- 응
And no one's contacting any embassy either.
아무도 어느 대사관에도
연락하지 않을 거야
What--what do you mean? Those men weren't Polish.
무슨 소리야?
이 자들은
폴란드인이 아니야
Their accents and uniforms were straight out of Minsk.
어투와 복장이
딱 민스크 출신이야
우릴 벨로루시로
데려가는 거야
They're taking us to Belarus.
Those guys were secret police?
The last proud branch of the Soviet militia.
비밀경찰이라고?
소비에트 민병대의
마지막 남은 자랑스런 지부지
Okay, um, we maintain our covers.
좋아, 어...
위장신분을 유지해야 해
그게 지침이야
That's protocol.
We deny any knowledge of the CIA's cooperation with Poland.
CIA와 폴란드와의 공조에
대해선 함구해야 하고
We know nothing about anyone smuggling weapons over any borders.
국경선에서 이뤄지는
무기 밀수에 대해선
아무것도 모르는 거야
Okay, we are just hikers. That's all.
알았지? 우린 그냥
등산객일 뿐이야
It's gonna be okay. We were trained for this.
괜찮을 거야
우린 훈련을 받았잖아
Both of us. Remember the exercises at the farm?
우리 둘 다
양성소에서 받은
훈련 기억하지?
I liked the ones where you practice code breaking.
암호 해독 과정은
좋아했는데
I wasn't exactly good at the field work.
현장 업무 훈련은
그다지 잘하지 못했어
You know, the-- You can do this.
그런...
할 수 있어
We can do this.
우리 둘 다
할 수 있어
Not because we calculate the right statistics,
but because we work together.
올바른 통계치를
계산해냈기 때문이 아니라
우리가 함께 하니까
Yeah.
그래
What do you think they want with us?
I dunno.
원하는 게 뭐길래
우리를 데려가는 거지?
글쎄, 외국 정부에 잡힌
등산객이 우리가 처음은 아니야
We're not the first hikers taken by a foreign government.
We make pretty good bargaining chips.
우린 제법 괜찮은
협상카드야
Tell me what you see.
뭐가 보이나요?
Annie and Reva carefully obeyed the border,
애니와 리바가 조심스럽게
국경선을 지키고 있어
but the Belarusians made an incursion into Poland to capture them.
하지만 벨로루시인들이
국경을 넘어 둘을 잡았어
Have they made any demands yet? No, but we expect them soon.
아직 요구는 없나요?
아니, 하지만
곧 요구해오겠지
I wish we had people in country.
우리 측 사람이
있었으면 좋겠는데
Do you want to pull some operatives from St. Petersburg?
상트페테르부르크에서
요원을 보낼까요?
I have a better idea.
더 좋은 생각이 있어
BERLIN, GERMANY
베를린
=독일=
Your references and experience
당신의 추천서와 경험은
are very impressive, Mr. Wilcox.
상당히 인상 깊군요
윌콕스 씨
It seems like you will be a great fit for our risk management division.
우리의 위기 관리 부서에
적임자일 거 같습니다
Thank you. It would be a privilege.
감사합니다
함께 한다면 영광일 겁니다
Well, I feel I have a good sense of your strengths.
당신의 강점에 대해선
충분히 들은 것 같군요
So let's move on to your weaknesses.
이제 당신의 약점을
이야기해보죠
Tell me about some mistakes you've made in your career
당신 경력상의 실수를
말씀해주시죠
and how you'd strive to avoid making them again.
실수를 반복하지 않기 위해
했던 노력에 대해서도요
I don't know if this qualifies as a mistake,
이걸 실수로 봐야 할진
모르겠습니다만
but perhaps I've been too much of a diplomat
예전의 저는 외교관 성향이
너무 짙었던 거 같습니다
in the past.
So sorry, please ignore that.
정말 죄송합니다
무시하셔도 됩니다
Please, excuse me. I'll just be a moment.
잠깐 실례하죠
곧 돌아오겠습니다
Hi, Joan.
Just finishing a meeting at London station.
네, 조안
방금 런던 지부와
회의 마쳤어요
I know you had a job interview in Berlin, but we can talk about that later.
베를린에서
면접 본 거 알아
하지만 그 얘긴
나중으로 미루자고
Really, Joan, do we-- Annie and Reva have been captured.
조안, 그걸...
벨로루시 쪽의 급습으로
애니와 리바가 생포됐어
An incursion by the Belarusians.
I need you to go to Poland.
폴란드로 가줘야겠어
Of course. What are the details?
물론이죠
구체적인 사항은요?
Auggie will send you all the intel we have to your encrypted cell.
오기가 암호화된 전화기로
우리 쪽 정보를 보내줄 거야
Hello, young ladies.
I'm Max Kupala.
반갑습니다
아가씨들
나는 맥스 쿠폴라요
Welcome to Belarus.
벨로루시에 오신 걸
환영합니다
You are under arrest for espionage.
여러분은 간첩 행위로
체포되셨습니다
Sir, there has been a terrible mistake.
저기요
이건 끔찍한 오해예요
We are just hikers
우린 그냥
등산객이고
enjoying the beautiful primeval forest you share with Poland.
벨로루시와
폴란드 국경의
아름다운 원시림을
체험하러 온 거예요
We never crossed the border into your country.
우린 절대 국경을
넘지 않았어요
- Is that a fact? - Yes.
그런 거요?
네
I'm sure you heard of those Americans
이란, 시리아나 북한의
국경을 넘은 미국인에 대해
on the border of Iran, Syria, and North Korea?
당신도 들어봤겠지?
They too said they were just hikers.
그자들도 "그냥 등산객"
이라고 하던데
- I wouldn't know-- - Former U.S. Presidents
그런 건 잘...
과거에 미국 대통령들은
그들을 구하기 위해
flew halfway over the world just to rescue them.
지구 반대편까지
날아갔지
They must be very important hikers.
아주 중요한
등산객이었나 보군
Nice bag. You bought this?
Yeah, in--in a camping shop in Toronto.
훌륭한 가방이군
아가씨가 산 건가?
네, 토론토의
등산용품점에서요
Let's see what else you bought here.
거기서 또 무엇을
샀는지 보자고
Ah, Gayle Beacham.
게일 비첨 양
Hello.
반갑소
Look here.
이걸 보게나
These readings are sensitive
이 판독기는
인치 단위까지
아주 정밀하게 판독하지
within inches.
So it must be pulling from multiple satellites.
여러 개의 인공위성에서
신호를 받을 거야
Military satellites.
군사 위성에서
You did not buy this in a shop.
이건 가게에서
산 게 아니야
Souvenir.
기념품이야
We'll use only civilian-made rides and weapons. This is off book.
우린 민간 수송편과
무기만 사용한다
이건 비공식 임무야
There are no post-mission reports on this one.
이번 임무엔
사후 보고서나
No paperwork of any kind. And if we crash or are captured,
어떤 종류의
서류도 없다
우리가 추락하거나
사로잡혔을 때
there are no extraction contingencies for us. Let's go.
어떠한 구출 작전도
없을 거야
가자
좋아, GPS 신호에
가까워지고 있어
All right, we're honing in on their GPS signal.
Stay frosty. Gentlemen, scopes out and scanning.
긴장을 늦추지 마
자세히 주변을 관찰해
There! Go, go, go, go, go.
저기다!
서둘러!
저 트럭을 놓치지 마
Do not lose that truck.
Check those guys out.
놈들을 맡아!
DON'T MOVE.
꼼짝 마!
Where are the two women you were carrying?
이송 중이던
여자 두 명은 어딨지?
Ned, translate for me. Tell him to get out of the truck.
네드, 통역해
두 녀석 모두
차에서 내리라고 해
His friend too!
Where are the two women you were carrying?
이송 중이던
여자 두 명은 어딨어?
He says he doesn't know about any women.
여자에 관해선
아무것도 모른답니다
비밀경찰이 돈을 주면서
이 트럭으로
The secret police paid him to drive this truck
from Hrodna to Pinsk.
그로드노에서 핀스크까지
가라고 했답니다
Joan, I found Annie's GPS, but no Annie.
조안, 애니의 GPS는 찾았지만
애니는 없어요
Where are we?
여긴 어디죠?
This is a terrible mistake.
이건 오해라니까요
우린 그냥 등산객이에요
We're just hikers. I promise.
약속드려요
I've never met a spy, but I imagine they look nothing like us.
스파이를
만나보지도 못했지만
우리와는 전혀 다른
사람들일 거예요
앉아
Sit.
If I could just call the Canadian embassy,
I'm sure we could sort this out.
캐나다 대사관으로
전화하게 해주시면
분명히 이 문제를
해결할 수 있을 거예요
There will probably be a reward for our safe return
우리의 안전한 귀환과
당신의 친절에 대한
and your hospitality, of course.
보상도 물론
있을 거고요
There are many problems with everything you say.
당신 말대로 하기엔
문제가 많아
But let us start with the problem of the phone.
일단 전화기 문제부터
생각하자면
There is no phone.
여긴 전화기가 없어
If there was, I would not let you use it.
전화기가 있다고 해도
사용하게 해줄 순 없지
If there was a phone and I did let you use it, it would be tapped.
전화기가 있고
사용하게 해주더라도
그걸 도청할 거야
So whatever you have to say to the Canadian embassy,
그러니 캐나다 대사관에
할 말이 있으면
you can say to me.
나한테 말해
Nothing to say?
할 말 없어?
You see, the lack of a phone is not your problem.
봤지? 전화가 없다고
문제될 거 없어
Please, you don't have to do this.
제발요
이러실 필요 없어요
First we eat.
우선 식사나 하지
Thank you. Spasibo.
고마워요
정말 고마워요
Stop. That could be poisoned.
안 돼
독이 들었을지도 몰라
They have had multiple opportunities to kill us already.
우릴 죽일 거면
벌써 얼마든지 죽였어
They're feeding us 'cause they need us alive.
식사를 주는 건
우릴 살려두겠다는 거야
Besides, it's rude to not eat what you're served.
게다가 차려주는데
거절하는 건 예의가 아니잖아
Well, I wouldn't want to be rude to our kidnappers.
그래, 납치범들한텐
예의를 차려야지
Eat.
먹어
I promise you, it's not poisoned.
확실해
독은 없어
요구액이 얼마죠?
The Belarusian's cable demands $60 million
벨로루시 쪽에선
애니와 리바의 무사 귀환에
for Annie and Reva's safe return.
6천만 달러를
요구했습니다
It's couched as urgent economic aid, but we all know what that means.
긴급 경제 구호라는
명목이지만
진짜 의미는
우리가 아는 대로
It'll go straight into the pockets of the secret police.
비밀 경찰의 주머니로
직행하는 거죠
Nevertheless, how quickly can we send the money?
그건 됐고, 얼마나 빨리
돈을 보낼 수 있죠?
We can set up an untraceable offshore account and wire--
추적 불가능한 국외 계좌와
송금을 준비할 수 있어요
Before we get to that,
Joan, what were your people even doing there?
그 이야기를
하기 전에
조안, 당신 요원들이
거기서 뭘 하던 거죠?
We were putting eyes on an extremely porous border.
매우 허술한 국경 지대에
감시 수단을 설치하고 있었죠
We suspect large caches of weapons
have been traveling over it
대량의 무기가 그곳을 통해
중앙아시아에서
유럽으로 넘어온다고
의심하고 있어요
from Central Asia into Europe. I just wish you'd given us a heads-up.
사전 통보가
있었다면 좋았겠군요
국무부에서도 함께
할 수 있었을 텐데요
The state department could have worked with you on this.
So is that why you're dragging your heels, because we didn't read you in?
그래서 꾸물거리는 거예요?
알려주지 않았다고?
No, it's just that we would strongly prefer
to wire the funds as a last resort.
아뇨, 우리의 입장은
자금을 송금하는 건
최후의 수단이
되었으면 한다는 거죠
My operatives have been captured.
내 요원들이
억류됐어요
최후의 수단이란 게
어떻게 보일 거 같아요?
In your view, what does a last resort look like?
It's what happens after diplomacy fails,
but we haven't tried yet.
외교 수단이 실패하면
그렇게 하겠지만
아직 시도해보지도
않았잖아요
One of my undersecretaries can go to Minsk.
내 차관 한 명을
민스크로 파견할 수 있소
외교에 의지할
시간이 없어요
We don't have time for diplomacy. Pay the money.
돈을 지불해요
If you're not comfortable with that,
I can send an extraction team.
마음에 안 든다면
구출팀을 보낼 수도 있어요
군대의 파견은 문제를
더욱 키우게 될 겁니다
A military presence would be even more problematic.
그럼 당신 말은
국무부에선
So you're telling me that the state department is not permitting me
둘을 데려올 방법 그 어느 쪽도
내가 추진하는 걸
to pursue either option to bring my people home?
허가하지
않겠다는 거예요?
Give me two days.
If our negotiations aren't fruitful by then,
we'll send the money.
이틀의 시간을 줘요
협상이 지지부진하면
그때 요구액을 지불하죠
그때까지 내 요원들의
안전은 당신이 보장하고?
And you can guarantee my officers' safety
until that time?
Joan, I have all my available resources on this.
조안, 모든 수단을
동원할 겁니다
We take this situation very seriously, I assure you.
아주 심각하게 사안을
다룰 거예요, 장담하죠
I don't want assurances. I want my people safe.
장담은 필요 없어요
내 요원의 안전이 필요하죠
Joan.
State department wants me to pull you back.
조안
국무부에선 널
철수시키라고 하고 있어
You want me to pull back now?
I said that's what they wanted.
지금 철수하라고요?
국무부에서 그걸
원한다고 했어
I want you to remain in country.
난 네가 벨로루시에
남아있는 걸 원해
Just find them, quick.
Check over there.
둘을 찾아
빨리
저쪽을 살펴보지
Thank you.
고마워요
So what's it like to work for the CIA?
그래...
CIA를 위해 일하는 건
어떤 기분이지?
I wouldn't know. I work in a travel bookshop in Toronto.
저야 모르죠
난 토론토의 여행 관련
서점에서 일해요
But for being an American hiker,
하지만
미국인 등산객으로서
you know a lot about this country.
이 나라에 대해
많이 알고 있을 텐데
안 그래?
I'm not American. I'm sorry. Canadian.
난 미국인이 아니에요
미안하군
캐나다인
I wanted to visit your country for a long time.
당신의 나라에서
예전부터 오고 싶어했어요
I admire the Belarusian people very much.
난 벨로루시 사람들을
정말 존경해요
Yeah, we're organized, hard-working.
그래, 우린 협동심도 있고
열심히 일하고
Very kind to foreigners.
외국인들에게
아주 친절하지
Your country has been sold, stolen, borrowed,
당신의 나라는
그동안 팔리고
강탈당하고
차용당하고
occupied, and destroyed by everyone from the Vikings to Stalin.
점령당하고
파괴됐죠
바이킹에서 스탈린에
이르기까지요
Even now you only exist because Russia allows you to.
지금도 당신이
이럴 수 있는 건
러시아가 이걸
용인하기 때문이죠
Eh, you learned all that in a travel book store?
그걸 다 여행 안내서
서점에서 배웠나?
I like to read about the places I'm gonna visit.
난 가고 싶은 나라에 대해
읽는 걸 좋아해요
Is that also where you learned to speak Russian
그래서 러시아어도
그렇게 유창한 건가?
like a school girl from Minsk?
민스크에서 온
여학생처럼?
I like research. Research?
난 연구하는 걸
좋아해요
연구?
This is not research.
이건 연구가 아니야
You didn't read a guidebook about my home country.
넌 내 조국에 대해
안내서 따윈 읽지 않았어
You read the CIA files.
네가 읽은 건
CIA 파일이지
And they are pretty good in analyzing
CIA는 그 지역 사람의
약점을 분석하는 일에
the vulnerabilities of a people, right, huh?
제법 훌륭하지 않나?
그렇지?
I just wish you could appreciate us
난 당신이 우리의
놀라운 회복력 말고도
for more than just our resilience.
다른 것도
인정해줬으면 좋겠군
We make a world-class motorcycle.
우린...
세계적인 오토바이를 만들었잖아?
MINSK를 말함
After being held against my will, I think I'll buy a Harley.
이렇게 날
납치했으니
할리 데이비슨을
살 생각이 드네요
You better watch your pretty mouth.
입 조심하는 게
좋을걸?
I work for my government
난 내 정부를 위해
일하지
너도 네 정부를 위해
일하는 것처럼
just like you work for yours. We both have a job to do.
우린 제각기
할 일이 있는 거야
Right?
안 그래?
Yours is to come here uninvited,
네 일은 초대받지 않고
이 나라에 오는 거고
and mine is to use your presence to help my country.
난 네 존재를 이용해서
내 나라를 돕는 거지
당신은 당신 나라를
돕는 게 아니에요
You're not gonna help your country.
The money you get from this will go directly to the secret police.
여기서 나오는 돈은
곧장 비밀 경찰로 가겠죠
And you'll get, what, 15%?
당신은 얼마나 받을까요?
15%?
Ten.
In both of our agencies,
우린 각자
소속기관이 있고
we have to work very hard to prove our worth,
우리 가치를 증명하기 위해
노력해야만 해
to separate ourselves from our colleagues, right?
동료보다 앞서나가기 위해서
안 그래?
I like working with my colleagues.
I have a family.
난 동료들과는
함께 일하는 게 좋아요
나에겐 가족이 있지
And to support them,
난 가족을
부양해야 하지
I have to prove myself all the time.
난 언제나
내 자신을 증명해야 해
I hope your agency understands
네 기관에서...
the simplicity of that.
이런 소박한 바람을
이해해줬으면 좋겠군
Like I said, I don't have an agency.
말했듯이
난 소속기관
같은 거 없어요
Then you will not stay here for much longer
그렇다면야 넌 여기
더는 머물 수 없겠군
in this cozy little house.
이 작고 아늑한 집에서
You have a good night.
좋은 밤 보내라고
Spasiba.
고맙군
I know auntie Annie has some stickers in here somewhere.
애니 이모가 여기 어딘가에
스티커를 뒀을 거야
I want the elephant ones.
코끼리 스티커는 내 거야
I know you do, sweetie. We'll find them.
그래, 알아
얼른 찾아보자
All right, now if I was an elephant sticker,
좋아, 내가
코끼리 스티커라면
I would be there.
여기 있을 거 같아
Mommy, did you find it? No, I didn't, sweetie.
엄마, 찾았어?
아니, 못 찾았어
Why don't you guys run along and get a snack?
And I will be right there.
다른 데 가서
과자 먹지 그러니?
엄마도 바로 갈게
You've reached Annie Walker at the Smithsonian Institution.
스미소니언 협회의
애니 워커입니다
If I am out of the office, these messages will forward to my cell.
제가 부재중이라면
메시지를 남겨주시면
제 휴대전화로 연결됩니다
Thank you.
고마워요
Yeah, hi, Annie, it's your sister.
안녕, 애니
언니다
Little oops. You left your passport here.
아차 싶은 일이 있어
여권 놓고 갔더라
I know you've been in New York all week,
so you probably didn't realize it's gone.
이번 주 내내
뉴욕에 있을 테니
안 가져간 걸
눈치 못 챌 건데
But if you're planning on traveling to Edinburgh
for work tomorrow, you're gonna need it.
내일 에든버러로 출장 가면
여권이 필요할 거야
어떻게 전해줘야 할지
바로 연락해, 알았지?
Call me right away so I can figure out
how I can get it to you.
Okay? Bye.
끊는다
Follow my lead.
내가 하는 대로
따라와
WE DID NOT TOAST OUR MEAL.
우리 식사에
건배하지 않는군요
I SEE. ITHOUGHT I WAS IN BELARUS....
그렇군요, 벨로루시에
왔다고 생각했는데
...WERE THE THRID TOAST IS ALWAYS MADE TO THE WOMEN.
세 번째 건배는 언제나
여성에게 바치는 곳이죠
BUT PERHAPS I AM REALLY IN MOSCOW.
아마 난 모스크바에
있는 모양이네요
WE TOAST YOU.
당신에게 건배하지
I DRINK WITH YOU.
같이 한 잔 하죠
NO, THE VODKA IS TOO STRONG FOR A LITTLE GIRL
안 돼
여자가 마시기엔
독한 술이야
보드카는 그냥
맹물이에요
VODKA IS JUST LITTLE WATER.
I CAN DRINK WITH MEN
난 남자와도
마실 수 있어요
I HAVE SPENT TIME IN ST. PETERSBUTG, AFTER ALL.
결국 여긴
상트페테르부르크였나 보네요
AND NOW WE MUST TOAST FOR THE FORTUNE OF THE MEAL.
이젠 풍년을 기원하는
건배를 하죠
이번엔 벨로루시를
위한 건배를!
AND NOW WE MUST TOAST TO BELARUS.
TO THE GREAT BELARUSIAN OLYMPIC TEAM.
이번 잔은 위대한 벨로루시
올림픽 대표팀을 위해!
쿠팔린카, 쿠팔린카
* 벨로루시 민요 "Kupalinka"
* Kupalinka, kupalinka *
어두운 밤
찾아 헤매네
내 딸은 어디에 있나?
내 딸은 정원에서
장미를 꺾다
You okay? My stride is roughly 3 feet,
괜찮아?
내 보폭이
대충 90cm고
times an average of 1, 700 steps per hour.
시간당 평균
1, 700 걸음을 걸으니까
Plus breaks. Based on the general topography,
쉬는 시간도 있었고
일반적인 지형에서
비추어 볼 때
I'd say we've gone about nine miles so far.
여태까지 온 거리가...
14 킬로미터 쯤
온 거 같네
That actually helps me.
Helps you do what?
그건 정말로
도움이 된다
무슨 도움?
Plan our route.
We've been heading southwest all morning.
경로 설정에
도움이 돼
아침 내내
남서쪽으로 왔으니까
Now we can either go west towards Brest
서쪽으로
브레스트로 가서
and cross the border before we hit the city
도시에 닿기 전에
국경을 넘을 수 있고
or we can go south towards Ukraine.
Poland's closer.
남쪽 우크라이나로
갈 수도 있어
폴란드가 가까워
There's a U.S. military base
미군 기지도 있고
and an embassy with a record of our visas and a direct flight home.
대사관에 우리
비자 기록도 있지
집으로 가는
직항편도 있고
So it's expected, and the secret police will be looking for us there.
따라서 예상 가능하지
비밀경찰은 그쪽에서
우릴 찾을 거야
It's also where the CIA will find us.
CIA에서도 우릴
찾고 있겠지
Langley doesn't know this country like the secret police.
랭리는 비밀경찰보다
이 나라를 몰라
이런 상황에선
지침대로 해야 해
In a crisis, we should stick to protocol.
We have a greater chance of being rescued.
구출될 가능성이
큰 쪽을 택해야지
Reva, we can't count on being rescued.
리바...
구출되는 건
계산에 넣으면 안 돼
We can't assume that the secret police
won't cross other borders to come after us.
비밀 경찰이 우릴 쫓아
국경을 넘지 않을 거란
보장도 없어
Doing the unexpected thing is the safer choice.
예상하기 힘든 선택이
더 안전한 선택이야
If we get caught again, they will not take us
to some country house in the forest.
다시 잡히면
숲 속의 전원 주택 같은 곳에
갇히지 않을 거야
They'll take us to prison.
감옥에 보내지겠지
Okay, fine.
좋아, 알았어
But I'm gonna keep counting our steps. I expected nothing less.
그래도 걸음은
계속 셀 거야
그 정도는 해줘야지
Auggie, just got your message.
오기!
자네 메시지 받았어
Branch, thanks for coming down.
I need a favor.
브랜치, 와줘서 고마워
부탁할 게 있어
A sister of one of my ops
found her old passport.
우리 요원 중 한 명의
언니가 여권을 발견했어
A NOC passport? Nope, civilian.
비공식 위장 여권?
아니, 민간인 여권
But my operative's cover is that she's overseas,
위장 상으론 현재
국외에 나가 있기 때문에
and I don't want her sister to keep digging. What do you need?
언니가 계속
파헤치게 해선 안 돼
필요한 건?
Who do you know at the Scottish affairs office?
스코틀랜드 정보부 쪽에
아는 사람 없어?
I know everyone. Then I came to the right man.
다들 알지
부탁할 사람을
제대로 찾았군
Hi, Joan. We hit a small snag.
네, 조안
작은 문제가 생겼어요
- Bad weather? - No.
- 날씨가 안 좋아?
- 아뇨
But the old saying's true:
What goes up must come down.
하지만 옛말이 맞더군요
올라간 것은
반드시 내려가더군요
We are going to have to re-rig the fuel control.
연료 제어 쪽을
다시 손봐야해요
How long will that take? Ned, how long is this gonna take?
얼마나 걸리겠어?
네드, 얼마나 걸리겠어?
All day.
온종일이요
Not long. It's not a problem.
별로 안 걸려요
문제되지 않을 거예요
난 지금 국무부에만
거짓말하는 게 아니라
Okay, because I'm not only lying to the state department
but to several members of Congress about your very existence in Belarus.
몇몇 국회의원들에게도
네가 벨로루시에 있다는
사실을 숨겼어
I need you to work quickly and very quietly.
서둘러서 아주 조용히
처리해야 해
비밀 경찰에서
널 발견하면
If the secret police find out you're there,
it could jeopardize Annie and Reva's safety.
애니와 리바가
위험해질 수 있어
Understood.
알았어요
영국 대사관
I don't think you understand. This is a very serious situation.
이해를 못 하신 거 같네요
이건 아주 심각한
문제라고요
My sister works for the Smithsonian,
and she was supposed to travel yesterday
제 동생이
스미소니언에서 일하는데
어제 에든버러로
출장 갈 예정이었어요
to Edinburgh on business, but she's forgotten her passport.
여권을 깜빡했다고요
보세요
See, here it is. She's not answering her phone, and I can only assume
전화도 받지 않고
제가 추측할 수 있는 건
that she's in some sort of airport security jail.
무슨 공항 유치장에
억류됐을 거란 거예요
Is your sister a criminal? She's traveling without a passport.
동생분이
범죄자인가요?
여권 없이 여행했다면
달리 어떻게 했을까요?
What else would they do with her?
Look, she's been all over the world, but she has no survival skills
걘 전 세계를
돌아다녔지만
이런 상황에서의 생존전략은
전혀 모르는 애라고요
As I've explained already, it's not possible to enter Scotland
말씀드렸다시피
유효한 여권 없이는
스코틀랜드 입국이 불가능해요
without a valid passport. If your sister doesn't have it with her,
동생분이 여권이 없다면
스코틀랜드엔 없는 거예요
then she's not in Scotland. Well, then where is she?
그럼 어딨다는 거죠?
괜찮아, 내가 맡지
You know what, it's all right. I got this.
Oh, my apologies.
사과드리죠
My name is Andrew, and I work directly with the ambassador.
제 이름은 앤드류고
대사 직속으로 일합니다
어떻게 도와드릴까요?
How may I help you? My sister, Annie Walker,
제 여동생
애니 워커가
is supposed to be traveling to Scotland on business.
스코틀랜드에
출장 갈 예정이었는데
She's forgotten her passport.
So it's very important that I get it to her.
여권을 놓고 갔어요
이걸 전해주는 게
정말 중요해요
Oh, of course. Oh, let's see.
그러시군요
어디 봅시다
런던을 경유하는 브리티쉬
에어웨이 항공편을 예약했군요
She's booked on a British Airways flight connecting through London.
I see here that the U.S. consulate in Edinburgh
여기 보이는 바로는
에든버러 미국 영사관에서
issued her temporary paperwork to allow her to enter.
입국에 필요한
임시 서류를 발급해줬군요
Thank goodness.
정말 다행이네요
I'd be happy to Fedex this to her via the consulate.
영사관을 통해 여권을
보내드렸으면 합니다만
They will contact her tomorrow about picking it up.
그쪽에서 내일
건네줄 수 있을 겁니다
Don't worry. Well, thank you.
걱정 마세요
고마워요
I can't tell you what a relief this is. My pleasure.
얼마나 안심이 됐나
모르실 거예요
도움이 되서
기쁩니다
Auggie, it's Andrew.
- 오기
- 그래
앤드류야
You owe me a very nice bottle of single malt, my friend.
자네 나한테...
근사한 몰트 위스키
한 병 빚진 거야
What are you doing? Do you hear someone coming?
뭐하는 거야?
누가 오는 소리가 들렸어?
No, I'm just checking to see if the water's safe.
아니, 물이 안전할지
관찰하는 거야
We're upstream, and it's constantly moving.
여긴 상류고
물살도 거칠고
No industry in the area.
주변에 공장도 없어
Yeah, that's what water should taste like.
Go ahead.
그래
이런 물 맛이야
마셔
I always used to make fun of my crunchy granola friends
늘 유기농에
환장한 친구들을
for taking bottles down to the stream to collect water, but now I get it.
물 받으러 계곡에 간다고
놀리곤 했는데
이젠...
이해가 되네
Still don't get tempeh though.
그래도 템페는 이해가 안 돼
인도네시아의 발효 음식
Uh, dark berries growing in the forest.
숲에서 검은 딸기
종류를 먹었다간
There's a 79% chance those will kill you.
79% 확률로
죽을 수도 있어
They're black elderberries. They're delicious. They're not poisonous.
블랙 엘더베리야
맛있고
독도 없어
Also good for fighting the flu.
감기에도 좋지
That information wasn't available at the farm or in the CIA file.
그런 정보는 훈련소나
CIA 파일에는 없었는데
My dad was in the military, so we moved around a lot.
아빠가 군인이셔서
이사를 자주 했어
When I was little, he was stationed in Sweden,
and there were a bunch of fruit trees on the base.
어렸을 때
스웨덴에서 살았는데
기지 주변에
과일 나무가 많았어
My sister taught me which ones were safe to eat.
먹어도 되는 걸
언니가 가르쳐줬지
In the summer, we'd stuff ourselves.
여름이면
배 터지게 먹었어
My mom loved to bake berry pie. We usually ate them all before she could.
엄마가 딸기 파이를
자주 해주셨는데
엄마가 만들기 전에
다 먹어치우곤 했지
Reva, look. Potato farm.
리바, 저기 봐
감자농장이야
I bet we'd get some real food and a warm place to sleep.
저기선 진짜 음식도 먹고
따뜻하게 잘 수 있겠어
이제 해가 지고 있어
Are you kidding? Why would I be?
농담하는 거지?
내가 왜 그러겠어?
We're fugitives, political prisoners on the run
우린 도망 중이야
우릴 간첩 혐의로 쫓고 있는
비밀경찰을 피해
from the secret police who have charged us with espionage.
도망치는 정치범이야
Look, we're not going up to some strangers in the middle of nowhere to ask for potatoes.
외딴 곳의
낯선 사람들에게
감자 좀 달라고
부탁할 순 없어
저 사람들은 집시야
These are Roma people.
They've been oppressed by the government for centuries.
They're not gonna report us.
수 세기 동안 정부가
탄압한 사람들이라
우릴 신고하지 않을 거야
How do you know that?
그걸 어떻게 알아?
- 'Cause I know. - So what's your plan?
- 알고 있으니까
- 그래서 계획이 뭔데?
You're just gonna walk up and introduce yourself,
그냥 들어가서
네가 누군지 소개할 거야?
explain to them that we just so happen
어쩌다 보니까
등산 장비랑 돈, 신분증
다 잃어버리고
to have lost all of our hiking gear, money, and identification?
여기 오게 됐다고?
Yeah. Good luck.
맞아
잘해봐
잠깐...
Where are you going?
Back to Poland. That's what procedure dictates.
- 어디 가는 거야?
- 폴란드로 갈 거야
그게 지정된 절차고
아까도 그렇게 해야 했어
And that's what we shoulda done before. Don't you understand?
이해 못 한 거야?
That's where the secret police will be looking for us.
거기서 비밀경찰들이
우릴 찾고 있을 거라니까
Great. Let them find me.
잘됐네
찾으라지
Because then they'll make an official demand for my release,
and the CIA will pay for it.
그럼 공식적으로
내 석방조건을 요구할 테고
CIA에서 몸값을
지급할 거야
그게 야생에서 헤매면서
딸기를 먹는 것보단 나아
Better that than wandering around in the wilderness eating berries.
Reva, come on. We talked about this.
리바, 그만해
얘기했었잖아
We can't let fear lead to bad decisions or to not trusting each other.
두려움 때문에
그릇된 결정을 하거나
서로를 불신해선 안 돼
Please, be careful.
Don't follow me.
조심해!
따라오지 마!
I'm not gonna leave you here. Neither of us should be alone!
널 두고 가지
않을 거야
우린 서로
떨어지면 안 된다고!
Reva!
리바!
Annie. I'm here.
애니?
여기야
Okay, I need you to answer a few basic questions.
좋아
기본적인 질문
몇 가지에 대답해봐
What's your name? Reva Kline.
이름이 뭐지?
리바 클라인
Where are you?
여긴 어디지?
Unfortunately still in Belarus.
불행히도
여전히 벨로루시지
Let me help you up.
일으켜 줄게
Okay.
됐어
Ugh, damn it.
젠장!
Okay, all we have to do is make it across that field.
좋아
저 들판만 지나면 돼
I know that you think that going to the farm is a bad idea,
농장으로 가는 게
안 좋은 생각이라고
생각하는 건 알지만
but you're hurt and we need help.
넌 다쳤고
우린 도움이 필요해
I'm right about these people. I'd bet my life on it.
여기 사람들에 대해선
내가 옳을 거야
내 목숨을
걸어볼 거야
Introducing ourselves to strangers out here
means betting both of our lives.
저 사람들에게
우릴 소개하는 건
우리 둘 모두의
목숨을 거는 거야
I understand. Come on.
알았어
가자
Zira.
쥬라
쥬라!
안녕
HELLO.
YOU HAVE PRETTY HAIR.
예쁜 머리네
THANK YOU.
고마워요
WE THANK YOU FROM OUR HEARTS.
진심으로 감사드려요
U ARE WELCOME.
천만에요
Reva. What?
리바
Wake up. They're coming for us.
일어나, 우릴 쫓아왔어
여길 벗어나야 해
We gotta get out of here. What?
뭐?
도와줄게
I'll help you.
SEARCH THE HOUSE.
집을 수색하겠다
아니
NICE NIGHT, ISN'T IT?
아름다운 밤이잖나?
THEY'RE NOT HERE
없습니다
- Auggie. - Any news?
오기
들어온 소식은요?
The Belarusians sent a new cable changing their demands.
벨로루시 쪽에서
요구 조건을 변경했어
Instead of $60 million, they now want 80 million.
6천만 달러가 아니라
이젠 8천만 달러고
And they changed the timeline we have to deliver.
기한 역시 변경했어
They want the money in 24 hours
or Annie and Reva will be sent to a government prison.
24시간 이내에
송금하지 않으면
애니와 리바를
정부 교도소로 보내겠대
That's strange. Prison is a standard leverage play.
이상하군요
감옥은 기본적인
압박 수단이야
아뇨, 왜 뒤늦게
조건을 바꾼 거죠?
No, I mean, why are they changing the terms so late in the game?
돈을 보내지 않을 거라
생각할 이유가 없는데
They have no reason to think we won't send the money.
Unless... What? Unless they've escaped.
만약...
왜?
만약 탈출했다면
얘기가 다르죠
Demanding more money in less time is supposed to make us panic.
더 짧은 시간에
더 많은 돈을 요구하면
우린 당황하겠죠
That way we'll send the funds before our operatives find a way to report in.
우리 요원이 상황을
알려오기 전에
돈을 받아낼
방법이란 거예요
이렇게 극단적이 아니었다면
좋은 생각이었겠죠
It'd be brilliant if it wasn't so desperate.
I can't act on that. It's just conjecture.
거기에 맞출 순 없어
그건 추측이잖아
- Jai. - Auggie, is Joan there?
제이
- 오기, 조안 있어?
- 옆에 있어
Right here.
이 지역 도처에
소문이 돌고 있어요
There are rumors throughout the countryside
of two foreign women traveling alone.
외국 여성 두 명이
여행 중이라는 거예요
Their descriptions match Annie and Reva's.
인상착의가
애니와 리바예요
Wherever they were being held,
they've escaped. I just said that!
어디에 잡혀 있었던 간에
탈출한 거예요
내가 방금 말했지!
Nothing? Nobody?
아무것도?
아무도?
Okay.
그럼 뭐
Joke all you want, but our situation on the ground requires that we be very creative.
농담은 맘대로 하는데
지금 이 바닥의 상황은
굉장한 창의력이
필요해졌다고
What do you mean "on the ground"?
이 바닥의 상황이란 건
무슨 뜻이야?
Just a figure of speech.
그냥 비유예요
Hey, if you need it, I've got some ideas about where they're headed.
혹시 필요하다면
어디로 향하고 있을지
나한테 생각이 있어
못 해
I don't think I can go any further.
더는 못 갈 거 같아
Yes, you can. I know you can.
할 수 있어
할 수 있는 거 알아
All right.
그래
Come on, come on. Come on.
서둘러, 어서
Here, I got you. Come on.
내가 부축해 줄게
힘내
Come on.
Look, we have to get across that river.
리바
우린 강을 건너야 해
We can walk back downstream and cross at a lower point,
하류의 낮은 지점에서
건너도 되지만
but with them after us, we don't have time.
저들이 쫓아온다면
시간이 많이 없어
Okay. We have to jump.
알았어
뛰어내려야겠네
두려운 거 알아
I know it's scary. But on the other side of that river is the Ukraine.
하지만 강 반대편은
우크라이나야
We can contact the CIA station and get a flight home.
CIA 지부에 연락해서
돌아갈 수 있어
I know you can do it.
넌 할 수 있어
Yeah. Yeah, I can.
그럼!
그래, 할 수 있어
Fear only prevents us from making clear decisions
두려움은 다만...
올바른 선택을
가로막지, 맞지?
in the moment, right? Right.
맞아
Besides, I swam varsity at USC.
게다가
난 남캘리포니아 대학
수영 대표였어
Come on.
가자
You okay?
괜찮아?
Come on, we're almost there.
No, my leg. I think it's broken.
힘내
거의 다 왔어
안 돼
다리가 부러진 거 같아
Put your arm over-- That's Max.
팔을 나한테 얹어
맥스야
Annie, they're here, okay? They found a way across the river.
애니
비밀경찰이 왔어
강을 건널 방법을
찾아낸 거야
It's Jai. Come on, come on.
제이야
가자, 힘내
...
- 괜찮아?
- 응
반가워요
It seems Belarus is using this fake village
as a holding station
밸로루시에선
이 유령 마을을
적성국가로 넘길
무기와 차량을
for weapons and vehicles destined for hostile nations.
보관하는 용도로
사용한 거 같아
The CIA and Warsaw have been informed of this development.
CIA와 바르샤바가
이 단지를 파악하게 됐고
They will be sending operatives to the area for further investigation.
그 지역으로
요원을 파견해서
추가 조사를
진행할 거야
Our case officers should be very proud of their good work.
우리 담당 요원들은
이런 커다란 성과에
자랑스러워해야
할 거야
Hey, congratulations
첨단 기술 데스크로
승진한 거 축하해
on your promotion to the advanced technology desk.
They're lucky to have you. Thanks.
그쪽으로선
행운이지
고마워
Maybe we can work together again.
또 함께 일할 수
있을 거야
Although I'd prefer for you to be the one in the field.
현장에는 너만 있는 편이
낫겠지만 말이야
I mean-- Clearly you don't need anyone to count your steps for you.
그러니까...
네 걸음 수를 세어줄
사람이 없더라도
넌 분명 잘 할 거야
I'll see you.
또 봐
Auggie. Hey there.
오기?
네
- Walk with me. - All right.
- 같이 걸어요
- 그러죠
I heard about Danielle.
언니 얘기 들었어요
I'm so sorry for all the trouble I caused you.
내가 일으킨 문제로
번거롭게 해서 미안해요
Well Branch did most of the legwork.
Well, I'll apologize to him then.
발품은 브랜치가 팔았어요
그럼 브랜치에게
사과해야겠네요
Uh-huh, hey, don't you ever apologize for any of it.
그 어떤 일에도
절대 사과하지 말아요
You have someone in your life who cares about you,
당신의 삶엔 당신을
위해주는 누군가가 있어요
who would take an entire day to go down to a foreign embassy
하루 온종일
외국 대사관에 들어가서
just to help you out. It's an amazing thing.
오로지 당신을
도와주려는 사람이요
놀라운 일이죠
Speaking of which, here's your passport.
말이 나와서 말인데
여기 당신 여권이요
And I texted your sister on your cell phone number
언니분에게 당신 번호로
문자를 보냈으니까
so she wouldn't be worried.
언니분이 걱정하지
않을 거예요
Thanks. No problem.
고마워요
별말씀을
Glad you're back.
돌아와서 기뻐요
You weren't worried about me, were you, Auggie?
나 걱정하지 않았어요?
오기?
Not for a second.
잠시라도
걱정한 적 없어요
- 잠깐만요
- 네
Jai said you basically gave him directions where to find me.
날 찾을 방향을
당신이 알려준 거라고
제이가 그러던데
How did you know I'd go to the Ukraine instead of back to Poland?
폴란드로 돌아가는 대신
우크라이나로 갈 거라고
어떻게 알았죠?
Because it's unexpected.
그게 예상 밖이니까요
You always do the unexpected thing.
당신은 늘 예상 밖의
일을 벌이죠
* I had a dream last night *
♬ Change the Time ♬
Josh Ritter
* I dreamt that I was swimming *
* and the stars up above *
* directionless and drifting *
* and somewhere in the dark *
* were the sirens and the thunder *
* and around me as I swam *
* the drifters who'd gone under *
왔구나!
You're back! What a trip. I'm exhausted.
대단한 출장이었어
지금 완전 녹초야
Oh, I got your text. So everything worked out with the passport?
문자 받았어
여권 문제는
잘 해결된 거야?
Yes. Thank you so much. Let me see it.
응
정말 고마워
나도 보여줘
Look at your cool stamp. Yeah.
스탬프 근사하네
맞아
So am I a hero or what?
어때?
내가 영웅이지?
You woulda been totally stuck without me, right?
나 없었으면
꼼짝 못할 뻔했지?
It's true. You got me home.
맞아
언니 덕분에
돌아왔어
All right, what else do we need around here?
또 필요한 게
뭐 있을까?
Coffee. Ice cream.
- 커피
- 아이스크림
피드백
whemie@gmail.com
00:15:33, 323 -> 00:15:35, 323
How much are they asking?